Lauro Pimentel

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Personal Statement

As a software engineer, my journey began before I entered high school: in 2016, I signed up for the Brazilian Computer Olympics event. Years passed, and I now work as software engineer for a Brazilian company, currently I am seeking new opportunities. Raised for several years in the U.S. and with a record of contribution working remotely, I am well equipped to implement a client's next concept into an active solution.

Employment History

Software Developer, TMAX, Remote

FEBRUARY 2023 — PRESENT

- Engineering of an QR-Code authentication feature on a Typescript React Native android mobile application, using cryptography algorithms for a B2B company.
- Continuous feature implementation and code debugging on an electric energy monitoring web platform built with Next.js using Typescript and Yii framework.
- Communication feature development for a solar panel audit system using Laravel framework.
- Engineered a library management mobile and web system with Laravel and react native.

Python Full Stack Developer, BeyTech IT Solutions, Remote

MARCH 2022 — JUNE 2022

- Developed a CRM Bitrix24 marketplace plugin called BTAX, using Django, MongoDB and PostgreSQL, integrated with the CRM it allowed Brazilian payment method and fiscal documents emission.
- Automation bot Implementation on the Bitrix24 platform through BTAX, enabling the retrieval of field content and data manipulation.
- Implemented issue resolution related to Django's REST framework authentication bearer token, which was initially failing to return upon API requests.

Python Full Stack Developer, Startup - InProcesses.com, Remote

JUNE 2022 — PRESENT

- Reengineering of the initial industrial management system (IMS) prototype from peppertools.com.br, allowing employee registration, inventory control, and service control.
- Identified problems uncovered by customer feedback, and tested, corrected or referred problems to appropriate personnel for correction.
- Evaluated code to ensure it met industry standards, was valid, properly structured, and compatible with browsers, devices, or operating systems

Details

55 11 92002 3609 lauropimentel12@gmail.com GitHub Linkedin

NATIONALITY

Italian, Brazilian

Education

Major in System Analysis & Development, Federal Institute of Brazil, Bragança Paulista

AUGUST 2021 — AUGUST 2024

Skills

Python JavaScript TypeScript PHP SQL - MySQL / PostgreSQL Django / Django REST Framework Selenium React Next.js **React Native** Laravel Yii WordPress HTML & CSS Bootstrap Git Kotlin

Relevant Courses

C

CS50X, Harvard University CS50W, Harvard University Android Development w/ Kotlin, SENAI/CEBRAE Full Stack Flask Developer, Pirple.com PHP Course, Sololearn PHP CRUD, Udemy Swift, Sololearn

Languages

Portuguese

English

IT manager, Peppertools.com.br, Hybrid

JULY 2018 — JUNE 2022

- Engineering of an Industrial management system, at first it was developed with Flask framework, due to maintainability had to transitioned to the Django framework, also using Django REST Framework, allowing Service order creation, edition, and production status.
- Developed a cross-platform app, for android and iOS, using React Native and JavaScript.
- Developed invoice creation feature that had an approval option for creating a new product production order. Each time a service order status changed, it would email the administrator describing which employee changed the status and the timing of production.

Side Projects

Eucompro.com, Remote

JULY 2022 — DECEMBER 2022

Worked on an auction and classified site, using PHP CRM, Git, hosting server, Cloudflare, translation, web design, business plan, & marketing. Freely open sourced on <u>GitHub</u>.

WordPress - E-commerce, Bragança Paulista

JUNE 2020 — OCTOBER 2020

Built an epoxy selling site with WordPress using woo-commerce, Elementor, and social plugins.

Covid-19 - Project, Bragança Paulista

JUNE 2020 — SEPTEMBER 2020

Worked on a Coronavirus information project with a group:

Debugged and developed in JavaScript, HTML/CSS, and deployed with Heroku. Freely open sourced on <u>GitHub</u>.

Startup landing page - B2MO, Bragança Paulista

OCTOBER 2019 — NOVEMBER 2020

Built a simple site with PHPMailer, OOP, and JavaScript, for a startup promoting their work on sustainable energy.

ONU - European Cultural Heritage, Bragança Paulista

AUGUST 2018 — DECEMBER 2018

Built a WordPress website for a European Cultural Heritage school's fair with each group posting a European country, freely open sourced on <u>GitHub</u>.

